Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we have an elementary level lesson all about going shopping.
我是Catherine，今天我们有一节初级课程，主题是购物。
That's right.
没错。
Today we are going with a guy to a shop and he's buying a new suit.
今天我们要跟一个男人去商店，他正在买一套新西装。
Okay, so lots of great words for men or for buying clothes for your husband or brother.
好的，所以有很多好词适合男士，或者为你的丈夫或兄弟买衣服时用。
Let's take a listen to today's dialogue.
让我们听听今天的对话。
We'll be back in a moment.
我们一会儿回来。
Hello, sir.
您好，先生。
What can I do for you today?
今天我能为您做些什么？
Hello.
您好。
I need a new suit.
我需要一套新西装。
I have an important interview next week, so I really need to look sharp.
下周我有一个重要的面试，所以我真的需要看起来精神利落。
No problem.
没问题。
We have a broad selection of suits all tailor-made so it will fit perfectly.
我们有种类繁多的西装，全部量身定制，所以会非常合身。
Great.
太好了。
I want a three-piece suit, preferably made from Italian cashmere or wool.
我想要一套三件套西装，最好是意大利羊绒或羊毛制成的。
Very well, sir.
好的，先生。
Would you like to have some shirts made also?
您还想做一些衬衫吗？
Sure.
当然。
I also take some silver cufflinks and a pair of silk ties.
我还要一些银质袖扣和几条丝绸领带。
Very good.
很好。
Now, if you will accompany me, we can take your measurements and choose the patterns
现在，如果您跟我来，我们可以量一下您的尺寸，并选择款式
for your suit and shirts.
用于您的西装和衬衫。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So a very simple dialogue about a guy needing a suit and he talked to the tailor apparently
所以这是一个非常简单的对话，关于一个需要西装的男人，他显然跟裁缝
about a couple of things.
谈了几件事。
Now why don't we take a look at some of those words in Language Takeaway.
现在我们来看看“语言要点”中的一些单词。
Well, first of all, a tailor is a person who makes clothes.
首先，裁缝是制作衣服的人。
So in this case, a man who makes suits.
所以在这个例子中，是制作西装的男人。
And the first thing that we have to talk about is the kinds of suits that he has.
我们要谈的第一件事是他拥有的西装种类。
He says, we have a broad selection of suits.
他说，我们有种类繁多的西装。
Okay.
好的。
So this adjective, broad, what does that mean?
所以这个形容词“broad”，它是什么意思？
It means wide.
意思是宽的。
You know, you can have a very broad street.
你知道，你可以有一条很宽的街道。
That means many cars can fit across it.
这意味着很多车可以并排通过。
But in this case, we're talking about a selection.
但在这里，我们说的是选择。
So that means a broad selection of suits, very, very many suits to choose from.
所以这意味着种类繁多的西装，有很多很多西装可供选择。
Okay.
好的。
So for example, if you go to a music store where they sell CDs and stuff like that, they
所以例如，如果你去一家卖CD之类东西的音像店，他们
might, they will have a broad selection of music.
可能会有种类繁多的音乐。
So you can have rap and hip hop and R&B, etc.
所以你可以找到说唱、嘻哈、R&B等等。
That's right.
没错。
Or the iTunes store has a broad selection of music.
或者iTunes商店有种类繁多的音乐。
You can choose basically anything.
你基本上什么都能选。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So he has a broad selection of suits and he said, well, great.
所以他有很多西装可供选择，然后他说，太好了。
I actually need a three-piece suit.
我实际上需要一套三件套西装。
Okay.
好的。
So there are different kinds of suits.
所以有不同种类的西装。
Some just have two pieces like pants and a jacket.
有些只有两件，比如裤子和外套。
But the kind that the man wants is a three-piece suit.
但这位男士想要的是三件套西装。
So that means there's a jacket, pants or trousers, some people might say, and a vest.
所以这意味着有外套、裤子（有些人可能会说长裤）和一件马甲。
Okay.
好的。
So yeah, you've probably seen this.
所以是的，你可能见过这个。
They look very nice.
它们看起来非常好看。
Basically under or over your shirt, you wear a vest.
基本上，在你的衬衫下面或上面，你穿一件马甲。
And so if you wear a vest with a suit, it's called the three-piece suit.
所以如果你穿马甲配西装，那就叫三件套西装。
You know who I'm thinking of right now who always wears three-piece suits?
你知道我现在想到谁总是穿三件套西装吗？
He's very famous, a football player actually.
他非常有名，实际上是个足球运动员。
Beckham?
贝克汉姆？
Yes.
是的。
Really?
真的吗？
David Beckham.
大卫·贝克汉姆。
I don't know if you guys watched the World Cup, but in the World Cup, David Beckham was
我不知道你们有没有看世界杯，但在世界杯上，大卫·贝克汉姆
always wearing a three-piece suit.
总是穿着三件套西装。
Wow.
哇。
In that heat, that's amazing.
在那么热的天气里，真了不起。
Yeah.
是啊。
Okay.
好的。
So we have a three-piece suit.
所以我们有三件套西装。
Now, we don't have a four-piece suit, do we?
现在，我们没有四件套西装，对吧？
I don't think so.
我觉得没有。
I don't know.
我不知道。
I don't think so.
我觉得没有。
I don't know.
我不知道。
But basically, tux, you have like the, on your waist, the cummerbund.
但基本上，燕尾服的话，你腰上会有那种腰封。
Oh, cummerbund.
哦，腰封。
That's what it's called.
它就是这个名字。
Okay.
好的。
Well, that's for a tuxedo.
嗯，那是针对燕尾服的。
Now, moving on, we talk about the materials of the suit.
现在，我们继续，来谈谈西装的材质。
And he said, well, I preferably want something made from Italian cashmere or wool.
他说，嗯，我比较想要意大利羊绒或羊毛做的。
Okay.
好的。
So Italian is an adjective that describes things that come from Italy.
所以“意大利”是一个形容词，用来描述来自意大利的东西。
And Italy is very famous for its fabrics and silk.
意大利以其面料和丝绸而闻名。
So in this case, we're talking about Italian wool.
所以在这个例子里，我们说的是意大利羊毛。
Cashmere is a very expensive, very soft kind of wool.
羊绒是一种非常昂贵、非常柔软的羊毛。
Okay.
好的。
And wool is basically a sort of material that comes from the sheep, from the hair of the
羊毛基本上是一种来自绵羊的材料，来自绵羊的
sheep.
毛。
That's right.
没错。
And so different sheep, different animals have different kinds of wool, and these have
所以不同的绵羊、不同的动物有不同种类的羊毛，这些羊毛
different prices.
有不同的价格。
So some are more expensive and some are cheaper.
所以有些更贵，有些更便宜。
Cashmere is very expensive.
羊绒非常昂贵。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
And he also is offered some shirts and he's like, yeah, sure, I'll take some shirts.
他还被推荐了一些衬衫，他说，好啊，当然，我要几件衬衫。
And I also need some silver cuff links.
我还需要一些银质袖扣。
Okay.
好的。
So when you close your shirts by your wrist, you usually have a button or in some cases,
所以当你扣上手腕处的衬衫时，通常有一个纽扣，或者在某些情况下，
something a little bit more fancy.
更花哨一点的东西。
And when it's more fancy, it's called a cuff link.
当它更花哨时，就叫做袖扣。
Yes.
是的。
You've probably seen it.
你可能见过它。
It looks like a small metal button that you can remove from your shirt.
它看起来像一个小金属纽扣，可以从衬衫上取下来。
It looks a lot better.
它看起来好多了。
It's kind of hard to explain, but just imagine on your wrist, you have a small metal button
这有点难解释，但想象一下，在你的手腕上，有一个小金属纽扣
that you can close your shirt at the wrist.
可以扣住手腕处的衬衫。
That's right.
没错。
And some people have very, very fancy ones with special pictures.
有些人有非常非常花哨的，带有特殊图案。
So you could have, for example, a car, if you love cars, or a diamond cuff link with
所以你可以有，比如，一辆车，如果你喜欢车，或者一个带钻石的钻石袖扣，
a diamond on it.
上面有钻石。
That's right.
没错。
So he wants a cuff links made of silver.
所以他想要银质的袖扣。
And also he wants a pair of silk ties.
他还想要一对丝绸领带。
Okay.
好的。
So a pair of means two.
所以“一对”意思是两条。
He wants two different silk ties.
他想要两条不同的丝绸领带。
And the tie is basically something that you put around your neck.
领带基本上是你戴在脖子上的东西。
Men wear these usually to the office.
男士们通常上班时戴这些。
And ones that are made of silk are usually more expensive.
丝绸做的通常更贵。
That's right.
没错。
So a silk tie.
所以是一条丝绸领带。
And okay, so we've pretty much covered everything that he needs.
好了，我们基本上已经涵盖了他需要的所有东西。
He wants a very nice suit with a lot of great accessories.
他想要一套非常好的西装，配有很多很棒的配饰。
Why don't we listen to the dialogue again, and we'll be back with Fluency Builder.
我们为什么不重新听一遍对话，然后我们会回来进行流利度训练。
Hello, sir.
您好，先生。
What can I do for you today?
今天我能为您做些什么？
Hello.
您好。
I need a new suit.
我需要一套新西装。
I have an important interview next week, so I really need to look sharp.
我下周有个重要的面试，所以我真的需要看起来精神利落。
No problem.
没问题。
We have a broad selection of suits, all tailor-made, so it will fit perfectly.
我们有多种西装可供选择，全部量身定制，所以会非常合身。
Great.
太好了。
I want a three-piece suit, preferably made from Italian cashmere or wool.
我想要一套三件套西装，最好是意大利羊绒或羊毛做的。
Very well, sir.
很好，先生。
Would you like to have some shirts made also?
您还想做一些衬衫吗？
Sure.
当然。
I'll also take some silver cuff links and a pair of silk ties.
我还要一些银质袖扣和一对丝绸领带。
Very good.
非常好。
Now, if you will accompany me, we can take your measurements and choose the patterns
现在，如果您跟我来，我们可以量一下您的尺寸，并选择
for your suit and shirts.
您西装和衬衫的款式。
So in Fluency Builder today, we have three very useful phrases that you can say when
所以在今天的流利度训练中，我们有三个非常有用的短语，当你
you're with the tailor at the store buying a suit.
在店里和裁缝一起买西装时可以用到。
The first one is, to look sharp.
第一个是，“看起来精神利落”。
That's right.
没错。
He says that he has a job interview, and he wants to look sharp.
他说他有个工作面试，他想看起来精神利落。
Okay, so to look means to have the appearance of, but sharp, what does this mean?
好的，所以“看起来”意思是拥有……的外表，但“精神利落”是什么意思？
Basically take it as a chunk or as a phrase, and if you look sharp, it means you look smart,
基本上把它当作一个整体或一个短语，如果你看起来精神利落，意思是你看起来帅气，
you look good, you look clean, you look very nice.
看起来好看，看起来干净，看起来非常棒。
So this is normally something we say to men.
所以这通常是我们对男士说的话。
You look really sharp today.
你今天看起来真精神。
Or I want him to look sharp.
或者我想让他看起来精神利落。
I'm going to buy him a nice silk tie.
我要给他买一条漂亮的丝绸领带。
That's right.
没错。
So to look sharp, as I said, to look very nice, very clean, very handsome.
所以“看起来精神利落”，就像我说的，意思是看起来非常棒、非常干净、非常英俊。
Okay, so looking sharp.
好的，看起来真精神。
And well, when we were talking about the suit, the person mentioned that all the suits are
嗯，当我们谈论西装时，那个人提到所有西装都是
tailor-made.
定制的。
All right, this is a very important phrase if you want to go shopping for clothes that
好的，如果你想买专门为你做的衣服，这是一个非常重要的短语。
are made for you.
为你量身定做的。
So something is tailor-made if the sizes are made only for fitting you.
所以，如果尺寸只适合你，那就是定制的。
That's right.
没错。
If you go to a department store and you buy a suit off of the shelf or the rack, it's
如果你去百货商店，从货架或衣架上买一套西装，那
not tailor-made.
就不是定制的。
But if the tailor makes it, he sews it to your size, then it's tailor-made.
但如果裁缝做，他按你的尺寸缝制，那就是定制的。
You know, wedding dresses are tailor-made.
你知道，婚纱是定制的。
Special suits are tailor-made.
特殊西装是定制的。
So this is usually an expensive kind of clothing.
所以这通常是一种昂贵的服装。
Okay, so it basically means the tailor, the person, made it especially for you.
好的，所以它基本上意味着裁缝，那个人，专门为你做的。
And the opposite, as you said, would be off the rack.
正如你所说，相反的就是现成的。
Off the rack.
现成的。
And this means that when you go to the store, you pick something, you like it, and you buy
这意味着当你去商店时，你挑一件，喜欢它，然后买
it.
下来。
No one is going to sew it to make it fit you.
没有人会缝制它来合你的身。
That's right.
没错。
And this is actually how most of us get our clothes.
这实际上是我们大多数人买衣服的方式。
You go to the department store, you get a pair of jeans, a t-shirt.
你去百货商店，买一条牛仔裤，一件T恤。
Obviously all that stuff is off the rack.
显然，所有这些东西都是现成的。
It's not tailor-made for your size.
它不是按你的尺寸定制的。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
But if you really want to get something tailor-made, you need to be able to talk to the tailor
但如果你真的想定制一些东西，你需要能和裁缝
about it.
沟通。
So he will usually say, let me take your measurements.
所以他通常会说我给你量尺寸。
This is our next phrase.
这是我们的下一个短语。
That's right.
没错。
The tailor mentioned that he wants to take them over there and take his measurements.
裁缝提到他想带他们到那边量尺寸。
So when the tailor says, I want to take your measurements or I need to take your measurements,
所以当裁缝说，我想给你量尺寸或我需要给你量尺寸，
what does that mean?
那是什么意思？
That means I need to measure parts of your body to help make this suit.
那意味着我需要测量你身体的部分来帮助做这套西装。
So he'll normally measure your shoulders, your waist, your hips, and how long things
所以他通常会量你的肩膀、腰、臀，以及长度
will be.
是多少。
So your arms and your legs.
所以是你的胳膊和腿。
And these are all important measurements to know how big or how small to make the suit.
这些都是重要的尺寸，用来知道西装要做多大或多小。
That's right.
没错。
So you need to take your measurements or you can also say you have to get measured.
所以你需要量尺寸，或者你也可以说你得被量尺寸。
That's right.
没错。
So to get measured or to take someone's measurements.
所以被量尺寸或给某人量尺寸。
These are key phrases for buying a tailor-made suit.
这些是买定制西装的关键短语。
Very good.
非常好。
Okay.
好的。
Why don't we listen to our dialogue one last time and we'll be back to talk some more.
我们最后再听一遍对话，然后回来再聊一些。
Hello sir.
你好，先生。
What can I do for you today?
今天我能为您做什么？
Hello.
你好。
I would like to order a new suit.
我想订一套新西装。
I have an important interview next week, so I really need to look sharp.
下周我有一个重要的面试，所以我真的需要看起来精神。
No problem.
没问题。
We have a broad selection of suits all tailor-made so it will fit perfectly.
我们有广泛的西装选择，全部定制，所以会完美合身。
Great.
太好了。
I want a three-piece suit, preferably made from Italian cashmere or wool.
我想要一套三件套西装，最好是用意大利羊绒或羊毛做的。
Very well, sir.
很好，先生。
Would you like to have some shirts made also?
您还想做一些衬衫吗？
Sure.
当然。
I'll also take some silver cufflinks and a pair of silk ties.
我还要一些银色袖扣和几条丝绸领带。
Very good.
非常好。
Now, if you will accompany me, we can take your measurements and choose the patterns
现在，如果您跟我来，我们可以量您的尺寸并选择
for your suit and shirts.
您西装和衬衫的样式。
So do you have any tailor-made suits, Marco?
那么，马可，你有定制西装吗？
I actually don't.
我其实没有。
I haven't...
我还没有……
Here to the office, I never wear a suit.
在这里上班，我从不穿西装。
We don't really need to wear suits all fancy.
我们不需要穿得很花哨的西装。
And there have been very few occasions where I've needed a suit.
而且很少有场合我需要穿西装。
So I actually don't have a suit at the moment.
所以我目前其实没有西装。
Not even one?
连一件都没有？
Not even one.
连一件都没有。
Not even off the rack?
连现成的都没有？
I have a few at home and I just haven't used them.
我家里有几件，但我一直没穿。
And probably they wouldn't fit anymore.
而且可能它们也不合身了。
This is the problem with getting things tailor-made as well.
这也是定制东西的问题。
The thing is that with a tailor-made suit, usually it's made to get bigger or smaller.
问题是，定制西装通常是可以变大或变小的。
So maybe the shoulders and the arms are the same, but if you gain weight or you lose weight,
所以也许肩膀和胳膊是一样的，但如果你增重或减重，
the tailor can make those small, small changes.
裁缝可以做那些小小的调整。
That's right.
没错。
Actually, I had a friend who got some tailor-made jeans.
其实，我有个朋友做过定制牛仔裤。
And I think that would be nice because sometimes, I don't know, jeans for me, they don't fit
我觉得那挺好的，因为有时候，怎么说呢，牛仔裤对我来说总是不合身。
well.
不合身。
Me either.
我也是。
There's a very famous company that does tailor-made jeans that I was thinking about going to because
有家很有名的公司做定制牛仔裤，我正考虑去试试，因为
I hate buying jeans off the rack.
我讨厌买现成的牛仔裤。
Yeah, they usually don't fit.
是啊，通常都不合身。
Either the waist is too...
要么腰太……
If I need a bigger waist, but then everything is too baggy and it just doesn't look right
如果我要大一号的腰围，那其他地方就太松垮了，看起来不对劲，
or everything is too small.
要么就全都太小。
So I think this is a very interesting thing, although I don't know how expensive it would
所以我觉得这挺有意思的，虽然我不知道价格会
be because getting tailor-made clothes is relatively expensive.
多贵，因为定制衣服相对比较贵。
It can be very expensive, although that's usually in America or in Europe.
可能会非常贵，不过那通常是在美国或欧洲。
In places like India and China, I think it's much more common to have things made to fit
在印度和中国这样的地方，我觉得定制合身的衣服更常见，
you, tailor-made.
量身定做。
This is a very interesting subject and actually, we are wondering if maybe you know a tailor,
这是个很有趣的话题，其实我们想知道，也许你认识裁缝，
you are a tailor or you've gotten things tailor-made for you.
你自己就是裁缝，或者你做过定制衣服。
Maybe you got married recently and you had a tailor-made tuxedo or a tailor-made wedding
也许你最近结婚了，定制了燕尾服或定制婚纱
dress.
礼服。
That's right.
没错。
So let us know.
所以告诉我们吧。
We can be found at EnglishPod.com.
你可以在EnglishPod.com找到我们。
We hope to see you there.
希望在那里见到你。
All right.
好了。
Bye, guys.
再见，各位。
This wasberg.com.
这里是berg.com。